Orkun T ARAN

Data Analyst

Email: orkunaran@gmail.com | Phone: + 90 5075178972 | Ankara / Turkey



<u>inkedIn</u>



Twitter



Kaggle



Portfolio



Google Scholar

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

- Python
- SQL
- Tableau

DATA SCIENCE / MACHINE LEARNING

- A/B Testing
- MySQL
- Statsmodels, Scipy
- SPSS
- Data Manipulation
- Data Cleaning
- Data Visualization (Tableau, seaborn, plotly, matplotlib)
- Excel
- Pandas, Numpy
- Scikit-Learn
- XGBoost
- Hyperopt, Optuna
- Git and Version Control
- Data mining, acquisition
- Probability / Statistics

SOFT SKILLS

- Data Driven
- Collaborative
- Fast learner
- Communication / extravert
- Ability to handle pressure and work under tight schedules
- Leadership
- Problem-solving
- Skeptical perspective
- Initiative | self-driven
- Responsibility

EDUCATION

Hacettepe University, Turkey

PhD. in Occupational Therapy (JAN. 2013 - DEC 2018)

MSc. in Occupational Therapy (FEB. 2010 - DEC 2012)

B.Sc. Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation (SEPT. 2004 - JUNE 2009)

ABOUT ME

An associate professor in health sciences with 12 years of research and analysis experience, willing to make a transition into the data analytics business as a Data Analyst / Scientist. My work experience has given me a comprehensive knowledge of clinical trials, statistics, research methodologies, healthcare terminologies such as ICD-10, lecturing, communication with stakeholders - NGOs - governmental agencies and writing detailed reports. Proficient in Python, MySQL, and SPSS to implement statistical analyses, machine learning models, data cleansing and EDA. Seeks to bring 12 years of research experience to a data analyst position in a goal-oriented, collaborative, diverse environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Data Analyst - 2021 - Present

- Scrape Amazon items, create a dynamic visualization for each item and create insights for possible products to sell for a FBA startup Ongoing project
- Helped a local bakery startup to determine product prices by gathering other bakery prices

Freelance Biostatistician, 2015 - Present

 Healthcare data analysis - Worked on more than 100 studies/projects/theses on Health Sciences, which included hypothesis testing, factor analyses – EFA and CFA, regression analyses, Stractural equation modelling, Cluster analysis, Generalized Linear Model,

Hacettepe University, Turkey, 2010 - PRESENT

- Managed and lead research teams, decided roles and research areas and Published above 40 <u>articles</u> above 70 citations
- Organized project budgets with high budgets (ie. 4.3m Euros) with Excel

DATA SCIENCE/ANALYSIS PROJECTS

2018-PRESENT

- Visualized <u>Turkey Femicides</u> with Tableau
- Cleaned data, imputed missings of <u>depression</u>, <u>anxiety and stress data</u>; <u>Visualized</u> key insights
- Cleaned and explored <u>the Coffee Quality</u> data with MySQL
- Visualized Global Burden of Disease Youth Mortality with Tableau
- Explored world happiness rankings between 2015 2019, investigated changes over years, and happiest and most unhappy countries. Plotted happiness related features with seaborn, matplotlib and Plotly.
- Applied K-prototypes clustering algorithm to a <u>marketing data</u>, investigated customer behavior and made suggestion according to clusters
- Explored <u>fetal health data</u>, compared features with A/B testing(Kruskall Wallis and applied post hoc analysis with Dunn test), applied XGBoost algorithm and hypertuned with Optuna, resulted 95% accuracy.